🙎 # 03, 1st Cross Rudra Layout, Mathikere Bengaluru-560054 🕥 Indian 🛗 04/04/1991 ☑ nithin.gs04@gmail.com 9900196066 Married Nithin Kumar GS Technical Lead **SUMMARY** 6 years of Experience in IT Industry with Service Delivery Lead and Technical Production Support. Strong Background on Incident, Problem

& performance of application in Production environments. Leadership and interpersonal skills. Responsible for the alignment of IT services to meet and where possible exceed the expectations of the business and clients, encourage and develop a high quality service delivery culture within the IT Service Delivery.

(Identify and resolves problems in a timely manner), Release Management and Change Management process to increases productivity, scalability

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

July 2019 - Sep 2020 **Technical Lead** TATA Consultancy Services

Bengaluru, India

☐ Team building, leadership, motivation, and mentorship ☐ Handling a Team of Sitecore Administration Support Representatives and L1 Helpdesk Team

Accountable for overseeing the day-to-day operations of the team, distributing the workload evenly amongst staff and making sure motivation

and performance levels are maintained. Daily activities include Content publishing, New Relic Monitoring, Code/Content Package Deployment Installation Issues, IIS binding request,

**URL** redirection etc ☐ Work with developers, stakeholders & SMEs to identify and resolve change and incident requests.

☐ Red Amber Green analysis

☐ Skills assessment and gap analysis

☐ Performing RCAs for production incidents and preventing reoccurrences. Participate in Client calls for application support in production related issues, Quality & Ticket Audits (Weekly, Monthly)

Responsible for creation of Corrective and prevention Actions (CAPA) and Weekly status report(WSR)

☐ Initiation of calls with the Knowledge Managers to improvise the overall process training materials and knowledge articles and sales conversion ☐ Performance management which includes overall agent performance and Improvising their KPI's

Responsible for Roster and Leave management of team members, managing any staff sickness levels and organizing the necessary cover. ☐ Staff performance management and Schedule management.

☐ Critical thinking and decision-making

Senior Engineer (Sitecore Administrator)

Mindtree Itd Bengaluru, India

July 2016 - July 2019

Perform configuration changes in the infrastructure like Dot Config, sitedefinition, Index creation files related to Assembly & Platform.

☐ Knowledge on Content Management Systems and Web Server Infrastructure, Windows ☐ Application Infrastructure Administration, Windows

clusters

Daily activities include content publishing, CSS, Packaging, New website request, node creation, name creation, IIS binding request, URL redirection.

Database clean activities to remove artifact data from the databases issue debugging on Workflow, CSS, Event Logging, Log viewer, Server

Downtime, APP Pool Recycle and Code/Content Package Deployment Installation Issues. ☐ Work with developers, stakeholders & SMEs to identify and resolve build or deployment problems.

☐ Monitors application for expected performance & Effective queue management to meet the SLA

Enterprise System Specialist (Command Centre)

Bengaluru, India Job Description:

Sept 2014 - July 2016

Jun 2011 - May 2014

80%

70%

90%

Completed 22 Months in Unisys as Enterprise System Analyst as a part of Cloud infrastructure services which includes managing multiple

Unisys Global Services, India Pvt Ltd

applications running on windows. ☐ Troubleshooting of various issues related to Windows servers, web servers, Handling CPU and Memory related alerts & Performing bulk server

reboot ☐ Troubleshooting the following issues on Windows Server 2003, Windows Server 2008 & 2008 R2, and Windows Server 2012 & 2012 R2.

☐ Installation and Upgrades of Windows ☐ Hands on experience in effectively handling various monitoring tools like Nagios, Xymon and Solarwinds.

☐ Monthly Patch Management of Windows servers (Standalone and Cluster servers) using bladeLogic and LANDesk. Work on Change Requests to perform rebooting of servers, maintenance activities.

☐ Handle patching for cluster servers, making sure that the resources are online during and post patching activity.

**EDUCATION** 

## New Horizon College of Engineering

B.E

Bengaluru, India

TECHNICAL SKILLS

## Sitecore Administration

	Production Support	70%	Newrelic	70%
	ServiceNow	60%		
PERSONAL SKILLS				

Confluence

Communication

**Decision Making** 

Kannanda

Telugu

90%

90%

80%

Octopus deployment, Dynatrace, Remedy, MWatch,

### Self-motivation Adaptability

Leadership

90% **LANGUAGES** 

# **AWARDS**

**English** 

Hindi

Tamil

**Operation Excellence Award** 

Global Leadership Award

Best Performer of the year

**COURSES** 

Leadership etiquettes and Management skills

**Advanced Excel** 

MOST PROUD OF

Creative Thinking, Effectiveness, Productivity

**Effective Business Communication** 

### Analyzing Issues, Decision Making, Project Management, Strategic Planning Team Work

**Planning** 

**Physical Organization** 

Collaboration, Delegation, Goal Setting, Group Leadership

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Sitecore Administration

Strategic Planning

# **INITIATIVES**

**Drive Metrics** 

Decision Making

☐ Expertise in CAPA and WSR Report. ☐ Implemented automation to reduce manual effort amongst the team ☐ Implementation of Productive tracker to balance the work load of the associates Allocating jobs and workloads to individual staff members based on their ability ☐ Implementing new initiatives and making sure all staff understand.

**Supervising Staff** 

Production Deployment & Support

Creating and tracking Priority 1 and 2 issues with responsibility for the timely documentation, escalation (if appropriate), resolution and closure

Managing Multiple Projects

#### ☐ Giving prompt and accurate information on individual staff member performance. ☐ Making sure all tasks given to staff are done on time and to the required standard ☐ Ensuring a clean, safe and friendly working environment for all team members.

of trouble tickets.

**HOBBIES** 

travelling

www.StylingCV.com

☐ Ensuring that there is a certain level is slack in the system to cover busy periods. ☐ Managing any staff sickness levels and organizing the necessary cover. ☐ Making sure that Health & Safety rules are strictly followed by all team members

☐ SWOT Analysis ☐ Root Cause Analysis.

IT SKILLS ☐ Handled technical issues within an enterprise environment

☐ Managing sick leaves and Adherence

☐ Hands on experience in Content Management, Packaging Deployment, New website request, Alert Monitoring.

☐ Incident and new request management using Remedy tool.

☐ Coordinating with onsite team scheduling activities.

photography cricket



STYLING 🗪